国外
我在
I joined the British Royal Navy
at the tender age of 17
我在
I joined the British Royal Navy
at the tender age of 17
17 岁时加入英国皇家海军，在 30 年的
and in three decades of service,
lived in worked in every ocean.
17 岁时加入英国皇家海军，在 30 年的
and in three decades of service,
lived in worked in every ocean.
服役生涯中，我在每一个海洋中生活和工作，
我亲眼目睹了
I witnessed firsthand
the hidden world of the high seas,
我亲眼目睹了
I witnessed firsthand
the hidden world of the high seas,
公海的隐秘世界，有时是
sometimes the only vessel
for hundreds of miles.
公海的隐秘世界，有时是
sometimes the only vessel
for hundreds of miles.
数百英里的唯一船只，
sometimes the only vessel
for hundreds of miles.
有时我会醒来 被
And other times I'd wake up
surrounded in a fishing fleet
有时我会醒来 被
And other times I'd wake up
surrounded in a fishing fleet
一个捕鱼船队包围，尽管
that, despite having powerful
technology at my fingertips,
一个捕鱼船队包围，尽管
that, despite having powerful
technology at my fingertips,
我的指尖拥有强大的技术，但我
I didn’t really know who they were
or what they’d been doing.
我的指尖拥有强大的技术，但我
I didn’t really know who they were
or what they’d been doing.
真的不知道他们是谁，也不知道
I didn’t really know who they were
or what they’d been doing.
他们一直在做什么，
那里是狂野的西部，流氓
It is a Wild West out there,
and rogue fishers ...
那里是狂野的西部，流氓
It is a Wild West out there,
and rogue fishers ...
鱼
流氓鱼正在很好地提取
rogue fishes are extracting --
well, they’re disobeying the laws
that we put in place
流氓鱼正在很好地提取
well, they’re disobeying the laws
that we put in place
违反法律的行为 我们为
well, they’re disobeying the laws
that we put in place
保护我们的海洋及其资源
to protect our ocean and its resources.
以及它们掠夺的
And they're pillaging
colossal amounts of fish.
以及它们掠夺的
And they're pillaging
colossal amounts of fish.
大量鱼类而采取的措施
Seafood,
五分之一的海鲜被认为是
one fifth of seafood is thought to be
caught illegally or is simply unreported.
五分之一的海鲜被认为是
one fifth of seafood is thought to be
caught illegally or is simply unreported.
非法捕获的，或者根本没有报告
And that's a crime worth
up to 23.5 billion dollars.
非法捕获的，或者根本没有报告
And that's a crime worth
up to 23.5 billion dollars.
，这是一种价值高达 25
And that's a crime worth
up to 23.5 billion dollars.
亿美元的犯罪行为
，这是 犯罪歪曲了科学，
And it's a crime that skews the science,
因此影响了我们渔业的可持续性，
so it affects the sustainability
of our fisheries,
因此影响了我们渔业的可持续性，
so it affects the sustainability
of our fisheries,
it threatens the health of our ocean
它威胁着我们海洋的健康和主要
and the well-being of millions of people,
生活在较贫穷国家的数百万人的福祉，
mainly in poorer countries.
And it's not just pirate fishing
而不仅仅是海盗捕鱼
在未来的海洋中受到威胁
that's threatening
the future of our ocean.
在未来的海洋中受到威胁
that's threatening
the future of our ocean.
Out at sea, oil spills
are going undetected
所有泄漏都
Out at sea, oil spills
are going undetected
未被发现，因此未受到惩罚
and therefore unpunished.
There’s a massive, unmonitored
growth in shipping,
oil and gas exploration and aquaculture,
to mention just a few.
正如我刚才提到的一些，航运石油和天然气勘探和水产养殖业在不受监控的情况下大量增长，
And this is piling pressure on an ocean
that's already stressed by climate change.
正如我刚才提到的一些，航运石油和天然气勘探和水产养殖业在不受监控的情况下大量增长，
And this is piling pressure on an ocean
that's already stressed by climate change.
这正在对
And this is piling pressure on an ocean
that's already stressed by climate change.
一个已经受到
And this is piling pressure on an ocean
that's already stressed by climate change.
气候变化压力的概念施加压力，
直截了当的事实是，
The straightforward fact is,
如果你不能 看到它你无法管理它
if you can't see it, you can't manage it.
And I know from experience,
you can't monitor the whole ocean
如果你不能 看到它你无法管理它
And I know from experience,
you can't monitor the whole ocean
，我从经验中知道你不能
And I know from experience,
you can't monitor the whole ocean
从船的甲板上监控整个海洋，
from the decks of ships.
但你来自太空，这是一个
But you can from space.
And these are interesting times
但你来自太空，这是一个
有趣的时代，因为看似
because seemingly intractable problems
are starting to yield
有趣的时代，因为看似
because seemingly intractable problems
are starting to yield
棘手的问题开始
because seemingly intractable problems
are starting to yield
屈服于技术人工智能的力量
to the power of technology, AI,
and global interconnectedness.
屈服于技术人工智能的力量
to the power of technology, AI,
and global interconnectedness.
和全球互联性
现在有成千上万颗
Up there right now,
there's thousands of satellites,
现在有成千上万颗
Up there right now,
there's thousands of satellites,
卫星
beaming back an enormous amount of data
from the remotest parts of our ocean.
卫星
beaming back an enormous amount of data
from the remotest parts of our ocean.
从我们海洋最偏远的地方传回大量数据
beaming back an enormous amount of data
from the remotest parts of our ocean.
如果我们能够利用这些数据使它
What if we could harness that data,
make it useful and available to people
who care about the ocean?
如果我们能够利用这些数据使它
make it useful and available to people
who care about the ocean?
对关心海洋的人们有用并可用，这要
make it useful and available to people
who care about the ocean?
归功于科学的快速进步
Well, thanks to rapid advances in
technology and AI, we can do that.
归功于科学的快速进步
Well, thanks to rapid advances in
technology and AI, we can do that.
技术和人工智能，我们可以
使用 GPS 位置数据和机器
Using GPS location data
and machine learning,
使用 GPS 位置数据和机器
Using GPS location data
and machine learning,
学习来做到这一点 Global fishing watch 构建了
Global Fishing Watch built
the first-ever live stream map
学习来做到这一点 Global fishing watch 构建了
Global Fishing Watch built
the first-ever live stream map
有史以来第一个实时流图来监控
to monitor the industrial fishing fleet.
工业捕鱼船队，
At the moment, we see some 70,000 vessels.
目前我们看到大约 70,000 艘船，
我们已将此信息公开并
We've made this information public
and freely available to the world.
我们已将此信息公开并
We've made this information public
and freely available to the world.
免费提供给 世界，
但技术在不断发展，谢谢，
But technology moves on.
Thank you.
但技术在不断发展，谢谢，
(Applause)
技术在飞速
Technology moves on rapidly.
There's new and emerging technology
that we need to embrace
技术在飞速
There's new and emerging technology
that we need to embrace
发展，我们需要
There's new and emerging technology
that we need to embrace
拥抱新兴技术，以便将这张照片提供给
in order to give this picture
to everybody who needs it.
拥抱新兴技术，以便将这张照片提供给
in order to give this picture
to everybody who needs it.
需要它的每个人，就像我们与
in order to give this picture
to everybody who needs it.
日本和韩国的合作伙伴合作时
Like when we were working with our
partners in Japan and South Korea,
日本和韩国的合作伙伴合作时
Like when we were working with our
partners in Japan and South Korea,
他们告诉我们的那样
they told us there was illegal fishing
suspected in North Korean waters
他们告诉我们的那样
they told us there was illegal fishing
suspected in North Korean waters
朝鲜水域涉嫌非法捕鱼，
they told us there was illegal fishing
suspected in North Korean waters
违反了
in contravention
of the UN sanctions there.
违反了
in contravention
of the UN sanctions there.
那里的联合国制裁，但当我们第一次在
But when we first took a look on our map,
地图上看时，我们可以看到很少
we could see very little fishing
捕鱼，因为这些船只没有
because those vessels were not sharing
their GPS location data,
捕鱼，因为这些船只没有
because those vessels were not sharing
their GPS location data,
共享他们的 GPS 位置数据，
as they should.
我们应该称他们为暗船 并且
We call them “dark vessels.”
And generally, dark vessels
are up to no good.
我们应该称他们为暗船 并且
And generally, dark vessels
are up to no good.
通常黑暗的船只是不好的，
And generally, dark vessels
are up to no good.
所以我们不得不求助于其他
So we had to turn
to other sources of data.
所以我们不得不求助于其他
So we had to turn
to other sources of data.
数据来源，我们查看了
We looked at satellite-based
radar and optical imagery,
数据来源，我们查看了
We looked at satellite-based
radar and optical imagery,
基于卫星的雷达和光学
We looked at satellite-based
radar and optical imagery,
图像，我们照亮了那个区域，我们
and we lit that region up.
We revealed an armada
of almost 1,000 vessels.
图像，我们照亮了那个区域，我们
We revealed an armada
of almost 1,000 vessels.
发现了一支由近千艘船只组成的舰队，
We revealed an armada
of almost 1,000 vessels.
这是最大的案例之一
It's one of the largest cases
of illegal fishing ever seen.
这是最大的案例之一
It's one of the largest cases
of illegal fishing ever seen.
曾经见过的非法捕鱼
But there's huge human impact too.
造成如此巨大的人类影响太悲剧了，
Tragedy.
因为更小、更摇摇晃晃的
Because they're smaller,
more rickety North Korean boats
could not compete with that vast fleet.
因为更小、更摇摇晃晃的
more rickety North Korean boats
could not compete with that vast fleet.
朝鲜船只无法与那艘
more rickety North Korean boats
could not compete with that vast fleet.
vas 舰队竞争，它们被推到
They were pushed further and further
out to sea, and as a result,
vas 舰队竞争，它们被推到
They were pushed further and further
out to sea, and as a result,
离海越来越远的地方，结果
They were pushed further and further
out to sea, and as a result,
数百艘船只将倾覆并被
hundreds of them would be capsized
to be washed ashore in Japan
数百艘船只将倾覆并被
hundreds of them would be capsized
to be washed ashore in Japan
冲上岸 在日本，船员
with the crew either starving or dead.
要么饿死要么死了，
我们公开了我们的调查结果，
We made our findings public
and as a result,
我们公开了我们的调查结果，
We made our findings public
and as a result,
结果
We made our findings public
and as a result,
我们迫使当局采取
we compelled the authorities
to take action.
我们迫使当局采取
we compelled the authorities
to take action.
行动，该地区的非法鱼类减少了
Illegal fishing in that region
has dropped by 75 percent,
行动，该地区的非法鱼类减少了
Illegal fishing in that region
has dropped by 75 percent,
75 条，我们没有看到
and we're not seeing hundreds of vessels
now washing ashore in Japan.
75 条，我们没有看到
and we're not seeing hundreds of vessels
now washing ashore in Japan.
数百艘船现在在日本海岸清洗
and we're not seeing hundreds of vessels
now washing ashore in Japan.
(Applause)
新闻是
The good news is
that the techniques we used
新闻是
The good news is
that the techniques we used
我们用来阐明
to illuminate what
was happening in North Korea,
我们用来阐明
to illuminate what
was happening in North Korea,
朝鲜发生的事情的技术，我们可以在
to illuminate what
was happening in North Korea,
任何地方
we can use anywhere and everywhere
和任何地方使用，让今天看不见的东西变得
to make the invisible visible.
可见，你们中的任何人都可以点击
Today, any of you can click
on the internet
可见，你们中的任何人都可以点击
Today, any of you can click
on the internet
互联网来探索
to explore roads and buildings on land.
陆地上的道路和建筑物，为什么我们不能
Why can't we do the same for the ocean?
做同样的事情 海洋 我们需要
We need to create a dynamic, complete map
创建
一个包含海上所有工业活动的动态完整地图，并
of all industrial activity out at sea
and make it available
to everybody for free.
免费提供给所有人
Well, thanks to the Audacious community,
we're going to do that using
GPS location data
and millions of gigabytes
of satellite imagery,
将使用 AI 绘制和监控
we’ll use AI to map and monitor
more than a million oceangoing vessels.
将使用 AI 绘制和监控
we’ll use AI to map and monitor
more than a million oceangoing vessels.
超过一百万艘海洋生长的船只
我们将监控整个工业
We will monitor the entire
industrial fishing fleet
我们将监控整个工业
We will monitor the entire
industrial fishing fleet
捕鱼船队和那些
and those dark vessels.
我们将添加到数十万艘
We'll add in hundreds
of thousands of cargo vessels,
我们将添加到数十万艘
We'll add in hundreds
of thousands of cargo vessels,
货船中的黑暗船只数万个油气结构
tens of thousands of oil
and gas structures,
货船中的黑暗船只数万个油气结构
tens of thousands of oil
and gas structures,
aquaculture farms and wind farms.
水产养殖场 和风力发电场有了
With this public information,
这些公共信息，
环保主义者将获得
conservationists will have
the information they need
环保主义者将获得
conservationists will have
the information they need
保护
to protect critical habitats.
国家地理原始海洋等重要栖息地所需的信息，
Like National Geographic Pristine Seas.
他们正在使用
They're using our data to help
work with governments and communities
他们正在使用
They're using our data to help
work with governments and communities
我们的数据来帮助与政府
They're using our data to help
work with governments and communities
和社区合作，以保护
to protect critical habitats
in seven marine parks
和社区合作，以保护
to protect critical habitats
in seven marine parks
七个海洋公园的重要栖息地，这些公园的总
with a combined area of more
than twice that of California.
七个海洋公园的重要栖息地，这些公园的总
with a combined area of more
than twice that of California.
面积超过 是加利福尼亚州的两倍多，
with a combined area of more
than twice that of California.
我们将为研究人员提供
And we're going to give researchers
the data they need
我们将为研究人员提供
And we're going to give researchers
the data they need
他们推进海洋科学所需的数据，
to advance ocean science.
我们将为媒体
And we’re going to give
the media, campaigners
我们将为媒体
And we’re going to give
the media, campaigners
活动家和公众提供
and the public powerful knowledge
about human activity out at sea.
活动家和公众提供
and the public powerful knowledge
about human activity out at sea.
有关海上人类活动的强大知识
and the public powerful knowledge
about human activity out at sea.
，这来得正是时候，因为
And this comes just in time
because after two decades of talking,
，这来得正是时候，因为
在 经过二十年的讨论，我们终于
we finally have a treaty to manage
the conservation of ocean life
在 经过二十年的讨论，我们终于
we finally have a treaty to manage
the conservation of ocean life
有了一项管理
we finally have a treaty to manage
the conservation of ocean life
海洋生物保护和
and the establishment of marine protected
areas out on our ocean.
海洋生物保护和
and the establishment of marine protected
areas out on our ocean.
在我们海洋上建立海洋保护区的条约，
(Applause)
这将是至关重要的，因为
And this is going to be critical because
有 200 近 200 个国家
almost 200 countries have committed
to protecting 30 percent of the ocean
有 200 近 200 个国家
almost 200 countries have committed
to protecting 30 percent of the ocean
承诺保护 30 个海洋 到
by 2030.
2030 年，他们将需要
And they will need tools like this
to uphold that promise.
2030 年，他们将需要
And they will need tools like this
to uphold that promise.
这样的工具来维护这一承诺
我们可以开发政府
We can develop the tools
that governments need
我们可以开发政府
We can develop the tools
that governments need
需要的工具来维护他们的承诺 我们可以
to uphold their commitments.
We can inspire a new wave
of ocean management
需要的工具来维护他们的承诺 我们可以
We can inspire a new wave
of ocean management
通过公共数据
through public data
和开放技术激发新一轮的海洋管理浪潮
and open technology.
Now, I might have salt in my veins,
和开放技术激发新一轮的海洋管理浪潮
but you don't need
to have sailed the seven seas
需要航行七
but you don't need
to have sailed the seven seas
大洋才能关心海洋的未来
to care about the future of the ocean.
地球上的所有生命都依赖它 它
All life on Earth depends on it.
提供我们呼吸的氧气 它
It's providing the oxygen we breathe,
调节我们的气候
it’s regulating our climate,
它提供数
and it's providing the food
that billions of people rely on.
它提供数
and it's providing the food
that billions of people rely on.
十亿人
and it's providing the food
that billions of people rely on.
依赖的食物 但海洋资源却没有
But ocean resources are not inexhaustible,
we’ve got to protect them.
依赖的食物 但海洋资源却没有
But ocean resources are not inexhaustible,
we’ve got to protect them.
取之不尽用之不竭我们必须保护他
But ocean resources are not inexhaustible,
we’ve got to protect them.
我们今天有机会做到这一点，这是
We have the chance
to do that today like never before.
我们今天有机会做到这一点，这是
We have the chance
to do that today like never before.
前所未有的我们可以一起为整个海洋提供免费的开放式访问
We can give a free, open-access
monitoring system for the entire ocean.
前所未有的我们可以一起为整个海洋提供免费的开放式访问
We can give a free, open-access
monitoring system for the entire ocean.
监控系统
We can give a free, open-access
monitoring system for the entire ocean.
我们可以统治
Together we can reign in
this outlaw ocean.
我们可以统治
Together we can reign in
this outlaw ocean.
这种户外活动
我们可以结束海盗捕鱼我们可以
We can end pirate fishing.
And we can transform ocean management
for the common good of all.
我们可以结束海盗捕鱼我们可以
And we can transform ocean management
for the common good of all.
改变海洋管理 为了
And we can transform ocean management
for the common good of all.
所有人的共同利益
And we can transform ocean management
for the common good of all.
谢谢
Thank you.
(Applause)
谢谢